### **Rob Christopher Atalla**

Kansas City Missouri, 64114 | 816.507.5957 <u>linkedin.com/in/ratalla816 | ratalla816.github.io/professional-portfolio</u> <u>rob.atalla@gmail.com</u>

## CAREER SUMMARY

Driven and tech-savvy professional with a relentless passion for efficiency and accuracy. Known for being teachable, personable, proactive, and facilitative, as well as a strong business acumen developed during almost a decade of logistics and P&L experience. Received formal training in full stack application development and management from the University of Kansas.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# PROBLEM SOLVER II / IOL / ICQA

Amazon | New Century, KS December 2021 - Present

- Troubleshoot and resolve edge case customer returns; includes updating item dispositions, repairing broken SKU's, moving inventory to proper container numbers, and using alternative methods to locate order numbers when an RMA is not available.
- Research inventory in odd locations to reconcile physical and virtual quantities and delete virtual quantities if inventory cannot be physically located.
- Inspects processed return items for quality issues, and updates resale conditions if necessary.
- Collaborates with managers and warehouse associates in multiple departments to manage efficiency, quality, and safety.
- Coaches associates on quality defects by issuing Mastermind tickets and performing sorter audits.
- Submit IOL reports and ICOA audits daily.

#### BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER

## Western Logistics Express | North Kansas City, MO April 2021 - September 2021

- Created relationships within client organizations through cold calling, network lead prospecting, and email campaigns.
- Analyzed market data and trends to develop customer pricing strategies.
- Sourced and managed vendors.
- Served as sales coach and accountability partner for new hires.
- Left in September 2021 to complete full stack web development program.

#### SENIOR ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

## Freightquote / C.H. Robinson | Kansas City, MO May 2014 - April 2021

- Seized single-source opportunities by leveraging proprietary Enterprise SaaS solutions.
- Responsible for sourcing and developing multiple division top-ten accounts.
- Demonstrated ability to negotiate resources and priorities with multiple stakeholders to drive business results.
- Conducted quarterly business reviews with all clients in portfolio.
- Managed day-to-day customer commitments and maintained service levels through use of metrics and analytics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python Node.js, Express.js

RESTful APIs SQL, Sequelize CompTIA A+ MongoDB, MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose Webpack, React JS, GraphQL Jest, Insomnia, Inquirer ORM, MVC, PWA, MERN

Amazon AWS S3 / DynamoDB

SOFT SKILLS

Organized and diligent Project management Context switching

Presentation delivery

Contract negotiation
Solution / Enterprise-level sales
Vendor management

Analytics

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

## CODE COMMAND | November 2021 FRONT END DEVELOPER / ASSISTANT PROJECT MANAGER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/code-command Deployment: code-command-team.herokuapp.com

- Collaborated on a team of two front end developers, and two back end developers.
- Developed project theme, title, and content.
- Selected, sized, and inserted images.
- Conducted daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconciled progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup, then communicated results to Project Manager prior to standup.
- Primarily responsible for development of component and container files. Assisted team members when needed.

## FORGE | September 2021 PROJECT MANAGER / FRONT END DEVELOPER / FLOATER GitHub: github.com/ratalla816/Forge Deployment: forge-team.herokuapp.com

- Managed a team consisting of two front end, and two back end developers.
- Prepared and analyzed all requirements and necessary documentation.
- Created mockup using Figma.
- Designed workflow model and established timelines.
- Conducted daily standup meetings with all team members. Reconciled progress with timeline goals, user story and mockup prior to standup. Adjusted workflow and communicated strategy and expectations to the team.
- Primarily responsible for development of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Handlebars files. Assisted back end developers when needed.

**EDUCATION** 

November 2021 CERTIFICATE – FULL STACK WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT The University of Kansas, Edwards Campus, Overland Park, Kansas

**Expected June 2022 BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION**California Coast University, Santa Ana, California